WILDAN KURNIA CANDRA

Purbalingga, Central Java 53353 | +6285939438777 | wildan.desperado@gmail.com

Summary

I am a person who enjoys every step of the coding process, I want to find solutions to problems and feel proud of my work when it helps others.

I work mostly as a back-end developer and am capable in Golang, PHP, and Node.JS. My areas of expertise are database management, creating RESTful APIs, and designing effective systems. I have experience with Agile approaches, and I'm constantly willing to learn new things and sharpen my experience.

Outside of work, i enjoy to ride along cities with my bike or just enganging conversation with my friend, i have keen interest on automotive, music, and games.

Experience

Back End Developer Komerce

Aug 2022 - Present Purbalingga, Indonesia

- Write and develop program code that is met the requirements, with minimal bugs, and in accordance with industry best practices.
- Conferred with front-end developers to construct algorithms and flowcharts.
- Collaborated with departments to discuss technical issues, software system design and maintenance.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for web and mobile devices
- integrate system with shipping provider such as JNE, SICEPAT, IDEXPRESS, SAP, NINJA, J&T.
- Do any required technical documentation especially API Docs.
- · Complete task that provided by Product Team.
- Maintain to ensure that the deployed code has no problems.
- Monitor and ensure the system developed is running as expected.
- · Assist customer support while on user report.
- Handle company core logic such as system shipment cost calculate, order service and user balance & transaction service.
- Contributed on 3 company products (Komship, Kompack, Komclass) and several services.

Fullstack Web Developer

Aug 2020 - Jul 2022

PT. Mardizu Sejahtera

Bekasi, Indonesia

- Planned and executed new app for internal staff to increase staff work effectiveness.
- Troubleshot problems and diagnosed system faults.
- · Optimized team training and staff development with builded internal app.
- Digitize repetitious documentation procedures for easier access to documents and logs.
- Research for new tech that can be implemented on company business.
- Build a company internal apps and landing page.
- Setting up and manage panel server including domains and SEO.
- Deploy to servers.

Freelance Web Developer

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020 Purbalingga, Indonesia

CV. Wahana Sukses Bersama

- Handled special projects designated by Product Manager.
- Created backup files on servers and directories to avoid data loss.
- Participated as Fullstack Developer build a core feature for Restaurant POS with several stock monitoring.
- Setup complete project on client.
- Synchronize local to cloud data.

Skills

- Golang (Gin)
- PHP (Laravel, CI)
- JS (Vue, Express)
- UI Framework (Bootstrap, Tailwind)
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- NoSQL (Redis)
- Container (Docker)
- Version Control (Git)

Education

High School: Software Engineering

SMK Negeri 2 Purbalingga

Apr 2016 - Apr 2019

Purbalingga

Projects

E- Arsip Digital **Fullstack** Mar 2023

Ministry of Marine Affairs and Fisheries (KKP)

- Designing encrypted database structure (MySQL) for securing the application data.
- Securing login with CAPTHA and Email OTP.
- · Layouting pages to fulfilled with modules.
- Build API (Laravel) for Frontend layer.
- Testing on developments server and bug fixing for ready to deployment.
- Maintain and backing up database.
- Importing existing archive data to app.
- Deploy to production.

SIRUPAT (Sistem Ruang Rapat)

Ministry of Marine Affairs and Fisheries (KKP)

Front End

Aug 2023

- Analyze app structure including backend data flow and the database.
- Layouting app pages (Vue Laravel).
- Consuming API that provided by backend team.
- Create Event Calendar Management like Google Calendar to manage the event.
- Add digital signature presence for guest to make sure the guest are attending the event.
- Manual testing and deploy to production.

SIMPEL (Sistem Monitoring Pelabuhan)

Back End

Ministry of Marine Affairs and Fisheries (KKP), TegalSari Harbour

Oct 2023

- Providing API (Golang) for front end team.
- Handle the key logic API of the app workflow for detecting ship position and status.
- Automatically detect ship while CHECK-IN / CHECK-OUT on harbour area.
- · Make harbour Geofences by coords.
- Build Websocket for ship monitoring on app dashboard.
- · Surface detection on coords for determine the coordinate are in water or ground based tile color (Node JS).
- Load testing API for avoid system failure due to handle thousands ship client.
- Implement "Sliding Windows" rate limiter for smooth out the spikes in traffic.

Kaznet (Kang Zaman Volunteer Network) PDI Bogor & Cianjur

Front End Jan 2024

• Analyze app structure including backend data flow and the database.

- Developing an app to meet metrics requirements and track every voter considering of the Bogor & Cianjur 2024 election.
- Layouting app pages (VueJS).
- Implement provided API from Backend.
- Deploy to production.







